# William Oakley

# Full Stack Web Developer

Wilmette, IL 60091 (512) 673-0029 wmoakley@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/william-oakley-49b7b618b</u>

GitHub: github.com/woaky1

Portfolio: https://woaky1.github.io/react-portfolio/

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Full Stack Developer and recent graduate from Northwestern's Coding Boot Camp with an extensive background in generating custom educational content for customers in the software industry. Able to see a product from multiple angles and collaborate with both a wide variety of team members and clients. Proven success creating interactive experiences for a variety of Fortune 500 companies as well as local and state governments.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Languages**: Javascript

Technologies: Git, Node.js, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, HTML, Cascading Style

Sheets, Bootstrap, Express.js

# **Projects**

## Chicago School Search

GitHub: github.com/Chicago-School-Information/school-info

Live Website: <a href="mailto:chicago-school-info.herokuapp.com/">chicago-school-info.herokuapp.com/</a>

- A website built to help Chicago citizens find data about their local public schools and provide them with contact information for their local aldermans.
- Built the Google Map functionality on the page.
- **Tech used includes**: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Google Maps and Google Geocoding APIs, Node.js, Sequelize, Node Express, MySQL

#### **Chicago Commute Checker**

GitHub: bit.ly/2rUg5id

Live Website: bit.ly/33QvrC0

- This is a web app that allows users to choose a CTA train line and enter their ZIP code for up-to-date weather and train alerts. The app also recommends whether the user should commute or work from home.
- Contributed mainly to the javascript logic.
- Tech used includes: HTML5, CSS3, Materialize, Moment.js, jQuery, Ajax

William Oakley Page 2 of 2

# **Clicky Game**

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/woaky1/clicky\_game">https://github.com/woaky1/clicky\_game</a></a>
Live Website: <a href="https://woaky1.github.io/clicky\_game/">https://github.com/woaky1/clicky\_game/</a>

- A memory game created using React.
- Tech used includes: React, Bootstrap, Node.js

# **EXPERIENCE**

Jellyvision, Chicago, IL - Production Specialist

NOVEMBER 2016 - JULY 2019

- Customized code and content in Jellyvision's ALEX products to meet the specific needs
  of several Fortune 500 companies, universities, and municipal governments.
- Tested for and fixed software bugs.
- Directed voice-over talent.
- Assisted with hiring new talent for the Production Department.

# Jellyvision, Chicago, IL - Writer/Director

JULY 2012 - NOVEMBER 2016

- Wrote new interactive conversations for clients as well as scripts for portions of Jellyvision's ALEX line of products.
- Worked with both clients and the creative team to make sure custom conversations satisfied client's needs while staying true to the creative vision.
- Directed voice-over talent for conversations.

## CompassLearning, Austin, TX - Lead Writer

JULY 2007 - JUNE 2012

- Wrote engaging multimedia scripts for educational software.
- Worked with animators, software engineers, and education experts to develop characters and story concepts.
- Copyedited ancillary worksheets and quizzes.

#### **EDUCATION**

Northwestern University, Chicago, IL - Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

**Emerson College, Boston, MA** - Master of Fine Arts in Creative Writing

Birmingham Southern College, Birmingham, AL - Bachelor of Arts in English

Graduation Honors: Magna Cum Laude and Phi Beta Kappa